# SHIVAM DUGGAL

(+1)4126262173 shivamduggal.9507@gmail.com

↑ ShivamDuggal4 ♥ ShivamDuggal4 ♥ Shivam Duggal ♠ shivamduggal4.github.io

### RESEARCH INTEREST

My research interests lie at the intersection of computer vision, computer graphics & robotics. I am particularly interested in topics such as scene understanding, 3D perception, 3D reconstruction, 2D/3D simulation, physics-based vision & robot learning.

#### EDUCATION

# Carnegie Mellon University

Masters of Science in Robotics (MSR)

- Advisor: Deepak Pathak

- **CGPA: 4.16**/**4** (till 2nd semester\*)

# Delhi Technological University (DTU, formerly DCE)

Bachelor in Technology, Computer Science (B. Tech)

- Aggregate: 83.7%, CGPA: 9.12/10

Aug 2021 - Present Pittsburgh, USA

Aug 2013 - Aug 2017

Delhi, India

### RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

# Carnegie Mellon University

Graduate Student Researcher

- Advisor: Deepak Pathak

### **Brown University**

Research Intern

Advisor: Srinath Sridhar

May 2021 - Aug 2021

Aug 2021 - Present

Pittsburgh, USA

Remote

# Uber Advanced Technology Group

Research Scientist I

- Advisor: Raquel Urtasun

<u>Uber Advanced Technology Group</u> <u>AI Resident (3 AI residents selected world-wide)</u>

- Advisor: Raquel Urtasun

Nov 2019 - Feb 2021

Toronto, Canada

Aug 2018 - Nov 2019 Toronto, Canada

# Awards & Honors

[\* Denotes All India National rank]

$\mathbf{Top}  0.2\%$	GeoSim nominated as Best Paper Candidate CVPR	2021
Rank $1/70$	Marketplace Hackathon, Amazon	2017
Rank $20/7937^*$	Codechef June Long Challenge	2017
Rank $10/1885^*$	Hackerearth Collegiate Programming Contest	2016
Rank <b>28</b> *	ACM ICPC India Finals	2016
Rank $29/2609^*$	ACM ICPC Amritapuri Regionals	2016
Rank <b>29/867</b> *	ACM ICPC Chennai Preliminary Round	2016
Rank $12/5693^*$	Codechef October Long Challenge	2016
Rank $1/130$ Interns	Flipkart Hackathon JUGAAD	2016

### PREPRINTS & SELECTED PUBLICATIONS

[\* Denotes equal contribution]

# [CVPR 2022]

<u>Shivam Duggal</u>, Deepak Pathak. "Topologically-Aware Deformation Fields for Single-View 3D Reconstruction." [Link]

- Proposed a framework for learning 3D object shapes & dense 3D object correspondences from just an unaligned category-specific image collection.
- The 3D shapes are generated implicitly as deformations to a category-specific signed distance field & are learned in an unsupervised manner solely from image collections & camera poses w/o any 3D supervision.

# [NeurIPS 22] (under review)

Trevor Houchens, Cheng-You Lu, <u>Shivam Duggal</u>, Rao Fu, Srinath Sridhar. "NeuralODF: Learning Omnidirectional Distance Fields for 3D Shape Representation." [Link]

- Proposed a 3D reconstruction approach that models object geometry by storing depth to object's surface from any 3D point in any viewing direction.
- Introduced mechanisms to transform other geometric representations (meshes, point clouds, voxels) to & from the proposed geometric representation.

# [WACV 2022]

Shivam Duggal\*, Zihao Wang\*, Wei-Chiu Ma, Sivabalan Manivasagam, Justin Liang, Shenlong Wang, Raquel Urtasun. "Mending Neural Implicit Modeling for 3D Reconstruction in the Wild." [Link]

- Recent **neural implicit shape modeling** methods show promising results on synthetic/ dense data but perform poorly on sparse/ noisy real-world data.
- Analysed the root cause behind such behavior & proposed a simple yet effective curriculum learning method, which lead to **much higher fidelity shapes**.

### [CVPR 2021]

Yun Chen\*, Frieda Rong\*, Shivam Duggal\*, Shenlong Wang, Xinchen Yan, Sivabalan Manivasagam, Shangjie Xue, Ersin Yumer, Raquel Urtasun. "GeoSim: Realistic Video Simulation via Geometry-Aware Composition for Self-Driving." [Link]

- Proposed a **geometry-guided simulation** procedure for generating **photo-realistic renderings** of real-world traffic scenes.
- Our proposed pipeline contains: (1) 3D Mesh Reconstruction, (2) 3D-aware Object Placement, (3) Novel-View Rendering, (4) GAN-based post-processing.
- Nominated for Best Paper Award!

# [ICCV 2019]

<u>Shivam Duggal</u>, Shenlong Wang, Wei-Chiu Ma, Rui Hu, Raquel Urtasun. "Deeppruner: Learning efficient stereo matching via differentiable patchmatch." [Link]

- Previous stereo matching methods are based on dense pixel-wise correspondence estimation, which bottlenecks their efficiency.
- Combined the strengths of deep learning & traditional search-space pruning technique, **PatchMatch**, to propose a real-time stereo matching algorithm **(62ms on KITTI)**, which is at par with SOTA methods.

[WACV 2019] Shamit Lal\*, <u>Shivam Duggal\*</u>, Indu Sreedevi. "Online video summarization: Predicting future to better summarize present." [Link]

- Proposed a multi-task Conv. LSTM architecture for generating video summary auto-regressively, which is at par with non auto-regressive methods.
- Augmented our summarization system with a **next frame prediction network** to assist it reason about the next frame's inclusion in the summary.

### INDUSTRY EXPERIENCE

Amazon, Hyderabad, India	(Software Eng.)	Aug 2017 - Jul 2018
Flipkart, Bangalore, India	(Software Eng. Intern)	Jun 2016 - Aug 2016
Parallel Dots, Delhi, India	(Machine Learning Intern)	Dec 2015 - Jan 2016

### Conference Reviewing

3DV 2022, ECCV 2022, CVPR 2022, WACV 2021, ICRA 2021, IROS 2021, SIGGRAPH Asia 2021

### SKILLS

Languages/ Tools & Frameworks Python, C/C++, LATEX/ Pytorch, Git, AWS

### OTHER PROJECTS

# Non-Exponential Radiative Transfer for Light Transport

CMU, Pittsburgh

- Studied the Radiative Transfer Framework (RTE) which governs the physics of light transport through a participating medium.
- Classical RTE models light transmittance (as an exponential function) only through spatially-uncorrelated participating mediums. We explored the affect of spatially-correlated participating mediums on RTE, by modeling light transmittance as non-exponential functions.

### Poisson Solver for Depth Completion

Uber ATG, Toronto

- Casted the problem of monocular depth completion using single camera image and sparse Lidar points, to a boundary value problem.
- Instead of directly predicting depth value per pixel, we developed an approach to first predict relative-depth estimates per pixel and then integrate them to predict the final depth value.

### Emotion Recognition on speech signals

DTU, India

- Implemented ensemble approaches and compared various algorithms for emotion recognition in speech signals using MFCC and energy as features.
- Publication: Emotion recognition on speech signals using machine learning, ICBDACI (2017) [Link]